Guide to the Barrett H. Clark Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1915-1953; Series III; 4.79 linear feet (12 boxes)
  - Printed material regarding plagiarism and copyright
    - An American Tragedy Film Version Pending Legal Contest, 1931 June 26 (Box 19)
  - Plays and Stories, 1875-1947 (Box 19)
    Contains: "The Past As A Key to the Future," by Louis E. Laflin, Jr., Reprint from Lawrenceville Literary Magazine (1945 June); "Advice on Make-Up," by John F. Baird (undated); "American Drama and World Drama" by Horst Frenz (1945 March); "The Real Source of Vachel Lindsay's Poetic Technique" by Davis Edwards (1947 April); "The Two Orphans" by N. Hart Jackson (1875); "Shenandoah" by Bronson Howard (undated); "An Arrant Knave" by Steele MacKaye (1941); "The Goodly Company" by Marion Morse MacKaye (1942); and "Facing Infinitude" by Marion Morse MacKaye (1942)
  - Analysis of You Can't Take It With You and Rash Moments and comparison of The Little Spitfire and Brown Sugar, undated (Box 19)
  - Printed material relating to Eugene O'Neill, undated
    - Photographs (original and re-produced in clippings), undated (Box 20)
    - Clippings by O'Neill, undated (Box 20)
    - Clippings about O'Neill, undated; 4 (Box 20)
    - Scrapbooks with clippings about O'Neill, undated (Box 21)
    - Programs, undated; 2 (Box 21)
    - Periodicals, undated; 2 (Box 21)
    - Provincetown postcards, undated (Box 21)
  - Pamphlets by Barrett H. Clark, 2 (Box 22)
    Contains: Maxwell Anderson (1933);West of Broadway (1935); Paul Green (1928); The Blush of Shame (1932); Lost Plays of the American Theater (1937); Speak the Speech (1930); The Modern Drama (1927); Oedipus or Pollyanna (1928); The Reading and Study of Plays for Enjoyment (1925); An Introduction to the Plays of Paul Green (1926); American Drama Text Project (1936); Preface for From Candles to Footlights by Melvin Schoberlin (undated); Guide to the Study of the Screen Version of Stage Door (1937); Our Most American Drama (1939); American Drama in it's Second Decade (1932); Professionalism in the American Theater (1951 May 2); Sidney Howard (1939 September 2); Broadway and it's Extensions (1953 February 13); Great Short Biographies of the World (1928 October); Playgoing at Home (undated)
  - Pamphlets with prefaces, introductions, and forewords by Barrett H. Clark, 1915-1951 (Box 22)
    Contains: Little Ol' Boy by Albert Bein (undated); Four Plays of the Free Theater (1915); How's Your Second Act by Arthur Hopkins (1918); Eight European Plays selected by Winifred Katzin (1927); Accent on Youth and White Man by Samson Raphaelson (1935); Big Lake by Lynn Riggs (1927); Mother Nature and Progress by Gustave Vanzype (1917); One Act Plays edited by Barrett H. Clark and Thomas R. Cook (1929); Crick Bottom Plays by E. P. Conkle (1928); Spindrift by Martin Flavin (1930); A History of Modern Drama (1947); Educational Theatre Journal (1951 May); and Authors' League Bulletin (1937 July)
  - Form letter for Dramatists Play Service, 1938 July (Box 22)
    2 copies
  - "Sauce for Propaganda," by Barrett H. Clark, Authors' League Bulletin, 1937 July (Box 22)
  - "Professionalism in the American Theatre," by Barrett H. Clark, Educational Theatre Journal, 1951 May (Box 22)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings by Barrett H. Clark, 1922-1924; 2 (Box 23)
  - Clippings of articles by Barrett H. Clark, 1916-1920; 3 (Box 23)
  - Clippings of articles, review, etc, undated (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of clippings 1925-1932 (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of clippings 1932-1938 (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of clippings 1936-1940 (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of clippings 1925-1937 (Box 24)
  - Scrapbook of articles and criticisms clipped from the New York Sun, 1917-1919 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook of reviews from The Drama, 1924-1931 (Box 25)
    Complete reviews from November 1924 to June 1931, when the magazine suspended publication
  - Translations by Barrett H. Clark, undated (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook of clippings, 1920-1940 (Box 26)
    Reviews and advertising on Eight European Plays, The Appleton Book of Short Plays, One Act Plays, The Blush of Shame and Maxwell Anderson
  - Scrapbook of clippings about Barrett H. Clark, 1935-1941 (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook relating to Great Short Novels of the World, undated (Box 26)
    Advertising and reviews of American and English editions
  - Miscellaneous clippings, undated (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook relating to A Study of Modern Drama, undated (Box 27)
    Contains advertisements, reviews and articles
  - Scrapbook relating to Great Short Stories of the World, undated (Box 27)
  - Scrapbook relating to Eugene O'Neill and America's Lost Plays, undated (Box 27)
  - Scrapbook relating to An Hour of American Drama, Speak the Speech, Oedipus or Pollyanna, The American Scene and World Drama, undated (Box 28)
  - Clippings, articles and other ephemera about Barrett H. Clark, undated; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Scrapbooks containing clippings, articles and other ephemera concerning Barrett H. Clark, undated; 2 (Box 29)
  - Pamphlets, off-prints, etc. by Barrett H. Clark, 1926-1953, undated; 2 folders (Box 30)
    General note
    Former call number: Za C546 +S1